Brandon Corey

in brandonmcorey | □ brandoncorey.dev | ♠ brandoncorey | ■ bcorey3660@gmail.com | ♠ Foxborough, MA

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with experience in full-stack development and data analysis. I am familiar with various programming languages and cloud technologies. I became interested in programming through my analytics work, resulting in a shift in focus to development.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Co-Creator

01/2024-present

DataLoaf, Remote US

- Developed a TypeScript querying service to facilitate event data retrieval and processing via a REST api
- Orchestrated AWS infrastructure setup and automation via a CLI tool written in Go that utilized Terraform to provision or tear down 50+ resources with a single command
- Implemented a scalable real-time event delivery pipeline using Amazon S3, Amazon Data Firehose, and Amazon Redshift, transferring up to 1 million events per second
- Developed a React frontend that utilized DaisyUI and TailwindCSS to display aggregations based on event type, aggregation, time-frame, and user/event filters
- Leveraged Docker with EC2 for deployment of backend services and Nginx for serving the front-end application
- Developed an SDK that sends requests to Amazon API gateway to place data into pipeline
- Authored 10+ SQL queries to perform common analytics aggregations to execute against Amazon Redshift
- Implemented a Python User Defined Function (UDF) for complex filtering of event and user attributes

Marketing Analyst (B2B) 06/2022 - 04/2023

Wayfair, Boston MA

- Utilized Google BigQuery to write advanced SQL scripts that aggregated email engagement data (OR, CTR etc.) for reporting
- Wrote and maintained supplier contact script used for customer segmentation in all Supplier Marketing campaigns
- · Used JavaScript UDFs and stored procedures in BigQuery to abstract complex logic that was routinely executed
- · Leveraged Data Studio to create/maintain dashboard visualizations for supplier-contact segmentation data
- Used DataDog and Grafana to set up slack alerts for email campaigns that were not operating as intended
- Automated internal emails based on event triggers via JavaScript's Google suite integration

</> </> SKILLS

Backend Node, TypeScript, Go/Golang, Python, SQL, MongoDB, Express

Frontend JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Query, TailwindCSS, DaisyUI, HTML, CSS, Recharts

Cloud/Infra Terraform, Docker, Nginx, AWS (EC2, Kinesis, Redshift, Lambda, S3, API Gateway, Cloudwatch)

Other Git, Github, Linux, HTTP, Websockets, SSE, REST, Jest, React Testing Library, BubbleTea

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts, Amherst ☑

2019 - 2022

B.S in Managerial Economics, College of Social & Behavioral Sciences

Launch School © 2022 - 2024

Online program focused on Software Engineering fundamentals